<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="items-weapons.xml"
                url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/drnaz/dnd-aurora-resources/master/homebrew/shadows-over-innistrad/items.weapons.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Whisper" type="Magic Item" source="Shadows Over Innistrad"
        id="ID_DrNaz_ShadowsOverInnistrad_MagicItem_Whisper">
        <supports>
            ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING,
            ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE,
            ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN
        </supports>
        <description>
            <p>
                Forged with a mercurial metal pulled from the Far Realm, light dances and shifts across this curved
                blade.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong><em>Dormant State.</em> The wielder gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this
                    weapon. Whenever a creature is struck with a critical hit from Whisper, the target must make a DC 13
                    Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of the wielder for 1 minute. On a success, they are immune
                    to
                    being frightened by this effect for the next 24 hours.</strong>
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong><em>Awakened State.</em> The bonus to attack and damage rolls increases to a +2. Additionally, a
                    target that is hit with this weapon takes an additional 1d6 psychic damage. The DC to resist being
                    frightened from a critical hit increases to 15.</strong>
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong><em>Exalted State.</em> The bonus to attack and damage rolls increases to a +3 and the
                    additional
                    damage taken increases to 1d8 psychic damage. The DC to resist being frightened from a critical hit
                    increases to 17. Whenever Whisper is thrown, but before it hits, the wielder can choose to transform
                    into shadow and merge with the blade, teleporting instantly to wherever the blade impacts. If the
                    target
                    is a creature, the wielder emerges adjacent to the target in a space of their choice. If they miss
                    with
                    the attack, the DM determines where the wielder teleports accordingly.</strong>
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="enhancement">1</set>
            <set name="damage" type="piercing">1d4</set>
            <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>