<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Items</name>
        <author url="https://criticalrole.fandom.com/wiki/Whisper">Critical Role</author>
        <update version="0.1.6">
            <file name="misc.xml"
                url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/drnaz/dnd-aurora-resources/master/homebrew/shadows-over-innistrad/misc.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Whisper" type="Magic Item" source="Plane Shift: Shadows over Innistrad"
        id="ID_DRNAZ_SHADOWSOVERINNISTRAD_MAGIC_ITEM_WHISPER">
        <supports>
            ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING,
            ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE,
            ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN
        </supports>
        <description>
            <p>
                Forged with a mercurial metal pulled from the Far Realm, light dances and shifts across this curved
                blade.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong><em>Dormant State.</em></strong>The wielder gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made
                with this
                weapon. Whenever a creature is struck with a critical hit from Whisper, the target must make a DC 13
                Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of the wielder for 1 minute. On a success, they are immune
                to being frightened by this effect for the next 24 hours.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong><em>Awakened State.</em></strong> The bonus to attack and damage rolls increases to a +2.
                Additionally, a
                target that is hit with this weapon takes an additional 1d6 psychic damage. The DC to resist being
                frightened from a critical hit increases to 15.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong><em>Exalted State.</em></strong> The bonus to attack and damage rolls increases to a +3 and the
                additional
                damage taken increases to 1d8 psychic damage. The DC to resist being frightened from a critical hit
                increases to 17. Whenever Whisper is thrown, but before it hits, the wielder can choose to transform
                into shadow and merge with the blade, teleporting instantly to wherever the blade impacts. If the
                target is a creature, the wielder emerges adjacent to the target in a space of their choice. If they
                miss
                with the attack, the DM determines where the wielder teleports accordingly.
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="enhancement">1</set>
            <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
            <set name="damage" type="piercing">1d4</set>
            <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Mantle of the Armored Soul" type="Magic Item" source="Plane Shift: Shadows over Innistrad"
        id="ID_DRNAZ_SHADOWSOVERINNISTRAD_MAGIC_ITEM_MOTAS">
        <description>
            <p>A sacred mantle. Laced with gold.</p>
            <p>When you wear this mantle, you are protected from harmful effects. You have advantage on all Charisma and
                Wisdom saving throws.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">artificer infusion</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Otherwordly Influence" type="Background" source="Plane Shift: Shadows over Innistrad"
        id="ID_DRNAZ_SHADOWSOVERINNISTRAD_BACKGROUND_OI">
        <description>
            <p>Your prayers and pleads for help are being answered. <em>By something out of this world</em>. You're
                slowly losing your mind. Every time you cast a spell, choose one </p>
            <h5 class="caption">Insane Incidents</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td>d100</td>
                        <td>Effect</td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>01-02</td>
                        <td>Nothing happens. Apparently your deity is bored of their own insanity for the moment.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>03-04</td>
                        <td>Other creatures perceive you as a talking grapefruit for the next minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>05-06</td>
                        <td>You turn into a frog for 1 minute. This effect ends early if you take any damage.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>07-08</td>
                        <td>You perceive a random creature you can see as a shapeshifter that transformed into yourself.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>09-10</td>
                        <td>You become blinded and deafened for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>11-12</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see begins babbling and is incapable of normal speech for the next
                            minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>13-14</td>
                        <td>The next time you touch a creature within the next minute. you cast *greater restoration* on
                            it.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>15-16</td>
                        <td>A random object within 30 feet of you shines dim light up to 10 feet.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>17-18</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see becomes knocked prone and cannot stand up for the next minute.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>19-20</td>
                        <td>An invisible force pushes a random creature you can see up to 10 feet in a random direction.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>21-22</td>
                        <td>You become frightened of a random creature you can see for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>23-24</td>
                        <td>You cast *feign death* on yourself.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>25-26</td>
                        <td>You feel an inexplicable but irrestible urge to eat an exotic fruit for the next minute.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>27-28</td>
                        <td>A random object you can see transforms into an ogre for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>29-30</td>
                        <td>A spectral tendril sweeps on you, dealing 2d8 acid damage and 2d8 necrotic damage.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>31-32</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see becomes invisible for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>33-34</td>
                        <td>For the next minute, whenever you move, a short sound of horn honks from your limbs.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>35-36</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see becomes charmed to you for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>37-38</td>
                        <td>You float three inches above the ground for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>39-40</td>
                        <td>You cast *inflict wounds* as a 3rd-level spell on yourself.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>41-42</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see turns into a cheese wheel for 1 minute. This effect ends early
                            if it takes any damage.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>43-44</td>
                        <td>A faint, gibbering noise manifests around you for the next minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>45-46</td>
                        <td>You cast *phantasmal force* on yourself.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>47-48</td>
                        <td>For the next minute, whenever you speak the word "it," you take 1 psychic damage.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>49-50</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see bursts into flame, taking 2d8 fire damage and 2d8 radiant
                            damage.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>51-52</td>
                        <td>You turn invisible for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>53-54</td>
                        <td>You fall unconscious for the next 8 hours. This effect ends early if you take any damage.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>55-56</td>
                        <td>You are hit by a bolt lightning, taking 4d8 lightning damage.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>57-58</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see casts *command* as a 1st-level spell on you. The command is
                            always "Atten-*tion!"*</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>59-60</td>
                        <td>An exotic fruit of your choice appears in an unoccupied space within 10 feet of you.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>61-62</td>
                        <td>Any armor or clothing you are wearing vanishes with a faint *pop.* It reappears in 1d6
                            minutes, forcibly wearing itself to you.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>63-64</td>
                        <td>An invisible force pushes you up to 10 feet in a random direction.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>65-66</td>
                        <td>You cast *calm emotions* on a random creature you can see.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>67-68</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see casts *lesser restoration* on itself.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>69-70</td>
                        <td>You gain vulnerability to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage until the end of your
                            next turn.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>71-72</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see casts *Tasha's hideous laughter* as a 1st-level spell on you.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>73-74</td>
                        <td>A random object you can see transforms into a badger for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>75-76</td>
                        <td>The next time you touch a creature within the next minute. you cast *dispel magic* on it.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>77-78</td>
                        <td>You begin babbling and are incapable of normal speech for the next minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>79-80</td>
                        <td>For the next minute, you can only speak in Deep Speech, even if you do not understand it.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>81-82</td>
                        <td>You become charmed to a random creature you can see for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>83-84</td>
                        <td>You and a random creature you can see regain 2d8 points.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>85-86</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see becomes stunned for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>87-88</td>
                        <td>You cast *zone of truth* centered on yourself.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>89-90</td>
                        <td>A random object within 10 feet of you "speaks" a short nonsense in your voice.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>91-92</td>
                        <td>For the next minute, you perceive all humanoid creatures as fruits, depending on their race.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>93-94</td>
                        <td>Your mind becomes scrambled, inflicting 4d8 psychic damage to yourself.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>95-96</td>
                        <td>You cast *sleep* as a 5th-level spell centered on yourself.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>97-98</td>
                        <td>A random creature you can see becomes frightened of you for 1 minute.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>99-00</td>
                        <td>You become immune to all damage except force damage until the start of your next turn.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </description>
    </element>
    <element name="Saint Raban's Ward" type="Magic Item" source="Plane Shift: Shadows over Innistrad" id="ID_DRNAZ_SHADOWSOVERINNISTRAD_MAGIC_ITEM_SRW">
		<description>
			<p>While holding this shield, you have a bonus to AC determined by the shield's rarity. This bonus is in addition to the shield's normal bonus to AC.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="3" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>